Franz Waxman Papers
Franz Waxman Papers
- Scores by Waxman
  - Rebecca (Selznick International Pictures), 1940
    - Mrs. Danvers Parts II, waxman_1137; Accompanied by floppy discs wrapping paper and "aaa_readme.txt" floppy discs content sheet. Note on the wrapping paper: "New Parts and scores on discs (Notator-Creator C-Lab software), Atari computer (Rebecca). Note on "aaa_readme.txt" reads: "(unable to read, "not formatted")".; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 20)
      HP; CE; VL; VA; VC; CB
    - Selznick; Danvers; Fire; Horns 01 (full scores), waxman_1131; Contains 4 files with ".SAF" file extension. Accompanied by floppy discs wrapping paper and "aaa_readme.txt" floppy discs content sheet. Note on the wrapping paper: "New Parts and scores on discs (Notator-Creator C-Lab software), Atari computer (Rebecca). Note on "aaa_readme.txt" reads: "(unable to read, "not formatted")".; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 20)
    - Szelnick Parts, waxman_1134; Accompanied by floppy discs wrapping paper and "aaa_readme.txt" floppy discs content sheet. Note on the wrapping paper: "New Parts and scores on discs (Notator-Creator C-Lab software), Atari computer (Rebecca). Note on "aaa_readme.txt" reads: "(unable to read, "not formatted")".; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 20)
      FL; OB; CL; BN; HN; TP; TB; TI; CH
    - Szelnick Parts II, waxman_1135; Accompanied by floppy discs wrapping paper and "aaa_readme.txt" floppy discs content sheet. Note on the wrapping paper: "New Parts and scores on discs (Notator-Creator C-Lab software), Atari computer (Rebecca). Note on "aaa_readme.txt" reads: "(unable to read, "not formatted")".; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 20)
      VI; HP; VL; VA; VC; CB
    - The Fire Parts, waxman_1132; Contains 9 files with ".SON" file extension. Accompanied by floppy discs wrapping paper and "aaa_readme.txt" floppy discs content sheet. Note on the wrapping paper: "New Parts and scores on discs (Notator-Creator C-Lab software), Atari computer (Rebecca).; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 20)
      FT; OB; CL; BN; HN; TP; TB; TI; MA
    - The Fire Parts II, waxman_1133; Contains 9 files with ".SON" file extension. Accompanied by floppy discs wrapping paper and "aaa_readme.txt" floppy discs content sheet. Note on the wrapping paper: "New Parts and scores on discs (Notator-Creator C-Lab software), Atari computer (Rebecca).; Floppy disk: 3 1/2 inch (Box 20)
      CY; HP; PF; VL; VA; VC; CB; NP
    - "Suite, engraved", computer files; 5 PDF files
  - Red Mountain (Paramount Pictures) (working title: "Quantrill's Raiders"), 1951 (Oversize 91.3)
    Music cue sheet - July 13, 1951
  - Reminiscences, See Come Back, Little Sheba (1953: Paramount Pictures).
  - Reunion in France (M-G-M) (working title: "Reunion"), 1942 (Oversize 91.5)
    Music cue sheet - Dec. 11, 1942
  - "Rhapsody for Piano and Orchestra" (Oversize 91.7)
  - The Ride to Dubno, See Taras Bulba (1962: United Artists).
  - Rosanna, see Ernest Hemingway's Adventures of a Young Man (1962: Twentieth Century-Fox) and Classic Film Themes Medley [III].
  - Run Silent, Run Deep (1958: United Artists) (Oversize 91.9)
    Music cue sheet - May 9, 1958
  - Sayonara (Warner Bros.), 1957 (Oversize 92)
    Music cue sheet - Nov. 20, 1957
    Piano conductor's score (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations
  - Scampolo, See Fur'n groschen Liebe/Ach, wie ist das Leben schon!.
  - Scherzetto, undated (Oversize 92.5)
  - Second Hungarian Rhapsody by Franz Liszt / arranged by by Waxman-Friedhofer (Oversize 93, A-B)
    Full conductor's score (Selections) - originals and reproductions
  - Seven Sweethearts (M-G-M) (working titles: "Tulip Time in Michigan," "Tulip Time"), 1942 (Oversize 93.3)
    Music cue sheet - Aug. 3, 1942
  - The Shining Hour (M-G-M), 1938 (Oversize 93.5)
    Music cue sheet - Nov. 15, 1938
  - The Silver Chalice (Warner Bros.), 1954 (Oversize 94, A-B)
    Music cue sheet - Jan. 21, 1955
    Restoration for Suite: Full conductor's score (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations, and holograph notes on instrumentation (photocopy)
  - Sinfonietta (New York: Boosey & Hawkes), circa 1956 (Oversize 95)
  - Sir Walter Raleigh, See British Grenadiers (march).
  - The Song of Terezin (Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania: Theodore Presser Company), 1966
    - Little Mouse for Piano Trio, computer files; 4 .mus files
    - The Song of Terezin (Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania: Theodore Presser Company), 1966 (Oversize 97)
    - The Song of Terezin (Westport, Connecticut: Fidelio Music Publishing Company, renewed 1994) (Oversize 96)
      bound reproduction of final study score & vocal score
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 96)
      final (uncorrected) study score & vocal score
  - Sorry, Wrong Number (Paramount Pictures), 1948 (Oversize 98)
    Music cue sheet, July 13, 1948
    Restoration, Introduction and Passcaglia / arranged by by Christopher Palmer: Full conductor's score - original and reproduction
    Restoration, Passacaglia "for concert band" / arranged by by J.D. Morsch: Full conductor's score - reproduction, Instrumentation list and photocopy of holograph notes, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions
  - Souvenir de Paris, See The Devil Doll (1936: M-G-M).
  - Spectrum: A Color Cycle For Jazz Ensemble (Oversize 99)
    Re-orchestration: Full conductor's score (Selections) - originals and reproductions, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions, and holograph notes on arrangement
  - The Spirit of St. Louis (Warner Bros.), 1957
    - Barnstorming for piano sextet, computer files; 7 .mus files
    - Prelude, Building the Spirit, Le Bourget, computer files; 74 .mus files
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 100, A-D)
      Music cue sheet: Feature - Mar. 4, 1957
      Trailer - Apr. 9, 1957
      Full conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions (partially bound)
      Orchestral parts (Selections) - original and reproductions, some with annotations
      Restoration: Full orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations, Holograph notes on instrumentation (photocopy)
  - The Story of Ruth (Twentieth Century-Fox), 1960 (Oversize 101, A-C)
    Music cue sheet - May 9, 1960
    Full conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions of original sketches
    Restoration, "Narrative version": Full conductor's score - original and reproduction, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations, Holograph notes on instrumentation (photocopy)
    Restoration, "Symphonic version":Instrumentation list, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations
  - Strange Temptation, See Alias Nick Beal (1948: Paramount Pictures).
  - Sunset Boulevard (Paramount Pictures), 1950
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 102, A-D)
      Music cue sheet - April 14, 1950
      Conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions, partially bound
      Restoration: Full conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions, Orchestral arts (Selections) - originals, Holograph notes on instrumentation (photocopy)
    - Unidentified, 1 zip file; File is corrupt and cannot be opened.
  - Suspicion (RKO Radio Pictures), 1941 (Oversize 102A)
    Production score - excerpted reductions, photostats
    Titles:
    PROD. #306 M:10 Main title / before the fact
    PROD. #306 M:60 Melbeck's office / before the fact
    PROD. #306 M:74 Looking for Johnny / before the fact
    PROD. #306 M:85 Lina alone / before the fact
    PROD. #306 M:94 The morning mail / before the fact
    PROD. #306 M:106 Too fast / before the fact
  - Taras Bulba (United Artists), 1962
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize 103, A-C)
      Selections: La Stella del Desiderio (New York: United Artists Music Co., c1962; Milano: Resolute Casa Editrice Musicale, c1962)
      Restoration for "The Ride to Dubno" (alternate title: "The Ride of the Cossacks") [Charles] "Gerhardt version": Instrumentation list, Orchestral parts (Selections) - reproductions, some with annotations, Full conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions, some with annotations
    - Miscellaneous, computer files; 73 .sib files
      requires Sibelius music software
  - Task Force (Warner Bros.), 1949 (Oversize 104)
    Music cue sheet (trailer and feature) - Sept. 2, 1948
    Restoration for "Liberty Fanfares" for concert band: Full conductor's score (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations, Instrumentation list, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals
  - That Hagen Girl (Warner Bros.), 1947 (Oversize 104.5)
  - Theme, Variations and Fugato for Jazz Orchestra (Los Angeles: Fidelio Music Co.), circa 1956 (Oversize 105, A-B)
    Orchestral parts - reproductions, some with annotations
    Holograph notes on instrumentation
  - This is My Love (RKO Radio Pictures), 1954 (Oversize 106, A-C)
    Music cue sheet - Oct. 22, 1954
    Lyrics sheet "third revision" - Apr. 28, 1954
    Conductor's score - original sketches with music notes bearing date May 5, 1954
    Restoration: Conductor's score (Selections) - original and reproduction
  - To Have and Have Not (Warner Bros.), 1945 (Oversize 107)
    Music cue sheet - Oct. 31, 1944
  - Tortilla Flat (M-G-M), 1942 (Oversize 108)
    Music cue sheet - Apr. 17, 1942
    Piano conductor's score (Selections) (bound reproduction with additional music cue sheet mounted on endpaper)
  - The Two Mrs. Carrolls (Warner Bros.), 1947 (Oversize 109)
    Music cue sheet (trailer and feature) - Feb. 28, 1947
    Restoration for Suite: Full conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions, some with annotations, Orchestral parts (Selections) - original, Holograph notes on instrumentation (photocopy)
  - Untamed (Twentieth Century-Fox), 1955 (Oversize 110)
    Music cue sheet - Jan. 26, 1955
    Restoration for Suite: Full conductor's score (Selections) - reproductions, some with annotations, Instrumentation list, Orchestral parts (Selections) - originals and reproductions, some with annotations, Holograph notes on instrumentation (photocopy)
  - The Very Thought of You (Warner Bros.), 1944 (Oversize 111)
    Piano conductor's score (Selections) (bound reproduction with undated music cue sheet mounted on endpaper)
  - The Virgin Queen (Twentieth Century-Fox), 1955 (Oversize 112)
    Music cue sheet - Sept. 1, 1955
    Re-orchestration for "British Grenadiers March" / arranged by by F. Waxman: Full conductor's score (traditional) with annotations - reproduction, Conductor's score "1st draft" - reproduction, Conductor's score "file master" - reproduction, Instrumentation list, Orchestral parts (master copy)
  - Young in Heart (Selznick International), 1938 (Oversize 113)
    Conductor's score - original sketches and photocopies
    Music notes and continuity
  - Unidentified fragments, original (Oversize 114)
  - Music cue sheets (photocopies) (Box 17)
    Cue sheets for the following:
    Men & Women (pilot, CBS Television), March 26, 1959
    Sporting Blood (feature film, MGM), July 3, 1940
    Strange Cargo (feature film, MGM), February 17, 1940
    Test Pilot (feature film, MGM), April 14, 1938
    Three Comrades (feature film, MGM), May 23, 1938
    Too Hot to Handle (feature film, MGM), September 13, 1938
    Unfinished Business (feature film, Universal), [1941] - original, not photocopy
    Unsuspected (feature film, Warner Bros.), [1947]
    The Virginian, "An echo of thunder" (television series, NBC), 8/5/66
    Whiplash (unidentified), undated
    Woman of the Year (feature film, MGM), January 8, 1942
  - Music cue sheets (photocopies) (Oversize 115)